<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Shakyra C. Cornelius - blog</title><link href="https://shakyracornelius.github.io/shakyracc/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://shakyracornelius.github.io/shakyracc/feeds/blog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://shakyracornelius.github.io/shakyracc/</id><updated>2022-07-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Alain de Botton: On Love | Digital Season Summary</title><link href="https://shakyracornelius.github.io/shakyracc/summary-alain-de-botton-on-love.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>shak</name></author><id>tag:shakyracornelius.github.io,2020-10-30:/shakyracc/summary-alain-de-botton-on-love.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his 2016 talk, On Love, philosopher, bestselling author and School of Life cofounder Alain de Botton explores what it actually means to live happily ever after. The warm and witty philosopher of the everyday talks about how romantic myths and misconceptions shape modern relationships, and examines what it might …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his 2016 talk, On Love, philosopher, bestselling author and School of Life cofounder Alain de Botton explores what it actually means to live happily ever after. The warm and witty philosopher of the everyday talks about how romantic myths and misconceptions shape modern relationships, and examines what it might mean to love, to be loved and to stay in love. 
&lt;br&gt;- Sydney Opera House&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a summary of that talk. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern idea of love comes from the art we consume. We are currently loving within a very historical/social context and living in an era of 
romanticism. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Romanticism tells us what we should expect from love.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assumptions: &lt;br&gt;
1. &lt;strong style="color:#3795BE"&gt;We all have a soulmate&lt;/strong&gt;. Finding them will eliminate loneliness in our lives. We will find them through instinct. this instinct presents itself as a special feeling (the crush). &lt;br&gt;
2. &lt;strong style="color:#3795BE"&gt;Love lasts forever.&lt;/strong&gt; "Till death do us part." &lt;br&gt;
3. No one has jobs and therefore has an infinite amount of time to focus on their love. &lt;br&gt;
4. &lt;strong style="color:#3795BE"&gt;Sex is the crowning expression of love.&lt;/strong&gt; It is the sincerest expression of your feelings. Therefore, any interest outside of the couple will be catastrophic. Adultery is a violation of everything romantics believe that love is. They have put weight on sex that previously wasn't there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Romanticism has been a catastrophe for our capacity to have good, long relationships.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we want a chance at succeeding at love we will have to be disloyal to many of the romantic emotions that got us into the relationship in the first place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Areas where romanticism has spelt difficulty for us in relationships:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 style="color:#2E7D9E"&gt; 1️⃣ It replaced an earlier vision of human nature which stressed how broken we all are.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romanticism insists on the purity and good nature of every human being. For romantics, children are always good. The child is the purest expression of humankind. The only thing that corrupts a child is society. i.e. We are all born good, angelic, perfect people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 style="color:#9e2e76"&gt; Why is this troubling for relationships?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark style="background-color:#2F0E24;color:#EFF7FA"&gt;It leads to the problematic dynamic which is: self-righteousness&lt;/mark&gt; Assuming anyone is perfect is troubling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 style="color:#9e2e76"&gt; How do we solve this? &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark style="background-color:#2F0E24;color:#EFF7FA"&gt;By insisting all of us are deeply crazy.&lt;/mark&gt; We all experience some level of trauma that distorts us from childhood. This trauma should be presented as a warning when we enter new relationships.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 style="color:#9e2e76"&gt; Why are we unable to conceive of ourselves as damaged and crazy therefore prone to self-righteousness? &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark style="background-color:#2F0E24;color:#EFF7FA"&gt;We all have very low levels of self-knowledge.&lt;/mark&gt; After all, the people in our lives have no motivation to shed light on our flaws. So, many of us end up thinking we're easy to live with. &lt;br&gt; &lt;mark style="background-color:#9e8b2e"&gt;SUGGESTION!&lt;/mark&gt; Ask your date "How are you crazy?" and give each other honest, none hysterical answers. &lt;br&gt; ❗We need them to be aware of their imperfections to warn and prepare potential partners. This reduces the chance for resentment to breed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="color:#2E7D9E"&gt; 2️⃣ It emphasizes instinct i.e. the special feeling.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychotherapy tells us the way that we love as adults is a reflection of the way that we learned about love as children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 style="color:#9e2e76"&gt; Why is this troubling for relationships?  &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark style="background-color:#2F0E24;color:#EFF7FA"&gt;The way that we learned about love as children is likely problematic.&lt;/mark&gt; Our parents may likely have damaged our vision of love. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking for a partner we end up wanting to find a familiar love, which is unlikely. If we grew up in unhealthy environments, having a partner who has a secure expression of love will feel foreign and strange to us, which leads to us rejecting secure love. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="color:#2E7D9E"&gt; 3️⃣ Its high regard for honesty. &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, we all lie very often, which is what society calls of us but somehow we perceive the relationship to be the place where we can finally be our pure, honest selves. We want to find someone who accepts all that we are, where secrets no longer flourish. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 style="color:#9e2e76"&gt; Why is this troubling for relationships? &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark style="background-color:#2F0E24;color:#EFF7FA"&gt;Because after the honeymoon phase has ended we find that ... No we cannot be 100% honest with this person lest we risk them retreating and ultimately losing our chance at love.&lt;/mark&gt; We have to edit in the name of love. This ends up feeling like a betrayal as it directly conflicts with the ideas of romanticism. Romanticism insists on authenticity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="color:#2E7D9E"&gt; 4️⃣ It never talks about the practical sides of life.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;eg. laundry; housework, raising children... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 style="color:#9e2e76"&gt; Why is this troubling for relationships? &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark style="background-color:#2F0E24;color:#EFF7FA"&gt;This sets up the expectation that intelligent, sensitive people don't bother about these types of things. &lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, there is no preparation and accommodation for the type of difficulties that may come in this area. &lt;mark style="background-color:#2F0E24;color:#EFF7FA"&gt;There exists an idea that true romantics could never argue over petty household things&lt;/mark&gt; eg. like a dirty towel on the floor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially there is a belief that the practical side of life has no place in a good love life. This is central to romanticism and a disaster for our love life.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="color:#2E7D9E"&gt; 5️⃣  You shouldn't talk too much to your lover. &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a sign of not understanding them. Having to explain yourself too much invites the idea that there is no chemistry. We want an intuitive understanding of each other without words. In the short term, this is fine, in the long term it is a disaster.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 style="color:#9e2e76"&gt; Why is this troubling for relationships?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark style="background-color:#2F0E24;color:#EFF7FA"&gt;It leads to an outbreak of sulking. &lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sulk: a feeling of hurt with another person. a wound that the other person has given you that you are not going to explain to them for the simple reason that they're supposed to love you and if they love you they're supposed to know (what the problem is).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romanticism tells us that love by its nature is wordless. Unfortunately even the most well-meaning people simply cannot understand all of us. They cannot read minds which goes against the expectations of romanticism.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="color:#2E7D9E"&gt; 6️⃣ It believes to love means to love every single thing about a person, even the imperfections. &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early stages of love, the imperfections of a person are part of what makes them so loveable...until. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 style="color:#9e2e76"&gt; Why is this troubling for relationships?  &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point in the relationship someone says if you love me, why do you criticize me? Romanticism tells us love and criticism cannot exist in the same space.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 style="color:#9e2e76"&gt; What is a better version of love?  &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the Greeks: love is an admiration for the perfect sides of another human being, for the virtues, and qualities. The accomplish­ments in the character and achievements of another person. You may be generous towards their flaws, you may be forgiving of them, but you don't LOVE them. The word love is reserved for admiration for what's virtuous and accomplished in another person. The Greeks believe love should be a process of mutual education in which two people endeavor to become better versions of themselves. They do this not to be cruel or bring each other down, but because they have the sincerest, best interest of each other at heart. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;❗Love is a process by which a teacher and a pupil are constantly rotating roles. Everyone is the teacher and everyone is the pupil at certain points and has lots of things to take on board. This isn't a sign that love has been abandoned but proof that love is in action. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 style="color:#9e2e76"&gt; Why are we, such bad teachers? &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many relationship arguments can be seen as failed teaching moments. Note: (1) we don't think it is legitimate to teach. (2) a good teacher is calm and relaxed. doesn't nag or shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is there hope for love?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes. &lt;mark style="background-color:#9e8b2e"&gt;Love is less of a feeling and more of a skill to be learned. &lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What skills do we need to develop?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 style="color:#2E7D9E"&gt; 1️⃣ Learn to see your partner as a small child from age 2 to 3.5.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with psychological wounds is that we can't see them and so our partners don't give us the accommodation that we need. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="color:#2E7D9E"&gt; 2️⃣ Learn to see your partner as a loveable idiot. &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 style="color:#2E7D9E"&gt; 3️⃣ Reconcile your habit of getting into crushes. &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that every human is problematic from close up and would without difficulty find a way to drive you mad with their mental distortions despite their charm and beautiful skin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark style="background-color:#2F0E24;color:#EFF7FA"&gt;The truth is: there is no right person for us.&lt;/mark&gt; Everybody will be wrong for us in substantial areas. &lt;mark style="background-color:#2F0E24;color:#EFF7FA"&gt;Compatibility is ultimately an achievement of love and shouldn't be its precondition. &lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right person isn't someone who agrees and condones every aspect of our character. ❗It is somebody who negotiates the difference between two people in a particular way with a particular generosity and humor.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How do you know whether you should leave someone?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can honestly survey your life, pinpoint all the things that are making you unhappy, and blame it on your partner, then leave. But if your sources of unhappiness cannot be blamed on your partner, then stay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When are we ready for love?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you conclusively accept that you are crazy. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you have a good handle on your partners' craziness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you have an absolute awareness that anyone you meet is very imperfect. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you're ready to do the laundry ad discuss towels ad infinitum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you're ready to not insist that others guess what is in your heart but you may even have to use words to spell it out very patiently over long periods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you're ready to believe that all of this with a dose of humor belongs to a sincere relationship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="blog"></category><category term="notes"></category></entry></feed>